Guide to the Central Washington University Board of Trustees, Expenditure Records 1892-1897
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Board of Trustees, Expenditure Records
1892-1897
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
RG032-08-14
Central Washington University, Board of Trustees
0.75 cubic feet 1 letter sized document cases and 1 letter half sized document case Correspondence, purchase inventories, and receipts in good condition
This collection contains financial records and correspondence relating to salaries of State employees, building construction and maintenance, and other expenditures associated with the early development of the Washington State Normal School (presently Central Washington University) from 1892 to 1897.
Historical Note
The Central Washington University Board of Trustees was established as part of a legislative act to create the Washington State Normal School at Ellensburg on March 28, 1890. The first board of trustees consisted of the Governor, the State Superintendent of Public Instruction and three others to be appointed by the Governor. The Trustees first met in the summer of 1890. The board of trustees was appointed to establish and review university policies and oversee the general management of funds and properties of the school. Currently the board is composed of eight trustees, seven of whom are appointed for six-year terms by the governor of Washington State with the consent of the Senate, and one of whom is a student appointee that changes yearly.
The bulk of this collection consists of records and correspondence sent and received by the Board of Trustees of the Washington State Normal School regarding materials purchased and services rendered by individuals and business organizations during the construction of Barge Hall from 1893 to 1895. The financial records include detailed purchase inventories and receipts, monthly salary reports of Normal School faculty and employees, and warrants, vouchers and payment claims sent to the State auditor. Records of notable importance include the files of the Van Fossen Contracting Company (1893-1894) which constructed Barge Hall and the C. F. Weber Company which furnished the building.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Organized in alphabetical order by type of record and within file folder by title of business organization or surname of individual. Chronological arrangement.
Some restrictions may apply.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State Normal School. Board of Trustees
Ellensburg (Wash.)
Central Washington University--History; Building construction
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
College administrators--United States
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, 1892 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, A-K, 1893 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, L-Z, 1893 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, A-F, 1894 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, G-L, 1894 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, M-N, 1894 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, P-Z, 1894 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, A-D, 1895 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, E-H, 1895 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, I-O, 1895 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, P-S, 1895 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, T-Z, 1895 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, A-G, 1896 (Box-folder 1-13)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, H-Q, 1896 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, R-Z, 1896 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Construction, Maintenance and Salary Expenditures, 1897 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Miscellaneous Records (Box-folder 2-4)
- Northern Pacific Railroad, 1894 (Box-folder 2-5)
- O. W. Lynch and Company, Furniture Dealers, 1894 (Box-folder 2-6)
- Superintendent of the State Normal School, 1893 (Box-folder 2-7)
- State Auditors Office – L. R. Grimes, 1893 (Box-folder 2-8)
- State Auditors Office – L. R. Grimes, 1894 (Box-folder 2-9)
- State Auditors Office – L. R. Grimes, 1895 (Box-folder 2-10)
- Van Fossen Contracting Company, 1893 (Box-folder 2-11)
- Van Fossen Contracting Company, 1894 (Box-folder 2-12)
- C. F. Weber and Furniture Company, 1894 (Box-folder 2-13)